<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Michiel Vlaminck</title>
    <link>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Michiel Vlaminck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ANALYST PV</title>
      <link>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/analyst-pv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/analyst-pv/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this project is to provide tools for fault localization, power loss quantification and improved diagnostics of PV power plants. A more efficient detection, diagnosis and localization of the fault will lead to a reduced time during which the fault can impact production. More information can be found on the project website.
My work in the project consists of developing image processing techniques to detect and classify anomalies that occur on solar panels including bypass substrings, junction box issues, diode issues, string issues and potential induced defects (PID).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP4DRONES</title>
      <link>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/comp4drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/comp4drones/</guid>
      <description>COMP4DRONES is a European project that aims to provide a framework of key technologies to facilitate safe and autonomous drones. It will ease the development of new applications and functionalities on the field of transport, construction, surveillance and inspection, logistics and agriculture. More information can be found on the project website. The project is in collaboration with the HSI team of imec and the company Airobot.
My work in the project focuses on the use case of inspection of critical infrastructure, such as off-shore wind turbines or bridges, by means of hyperspectral imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIA</title>
      <link>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/aria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/aria/</guid>
      <description>The ICON project Augmented Reality for Industrial Applications was the follow-up project of GIPA. This time, the goal was to develop a guidance application for maintenance tasks on complex industrial machinery. By means of proof of concept we focused on the replacement of an oil filter in a cooling container of the company Evonik in Antwerp. More specifically, we made it possible for a layman to be guided using visual cues while wearing a head mounted device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIPA</title>
      <link>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/gipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michiel-vlaminck.github.io/projects/gipa/</guid>
      <description>The ICON project GIPA or Generic Interoperability Platform for Augmented reality applications took place in 2014 and 2015. The aim was to develop a generic AR platform able to serve a whole range of applications including but not limited to remote collaboration, remote expert aid, serious gaming and training, critical infrastructure management and disaster or crisis support. As an example use case, we focused on the application of &amp;lsquo;as-built-as-planned&amp;rsquo;, in which the goal is to give architects the ability to verify whether or not a construction is built according to their plans.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>